Guide to the Samuel Stark, Movie and theater directors, writers, producers, songwriters, etc.: photographs, 1916-1963
Department of Special Collections
Samuel Stark, Movie and theater directors, writers, producers, songwriters, etc.: photographs,
1916-1963
MSS PHOTO 173
Stark, Samuel
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Samuel Stark, 1969.
Provenance
Gift of Samuel Stark, 1969; part of the Stanford Libraries' Theater collection.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Motion picture industry.; Motion picture producers and directors--United States.; Motion pictures--History.; Photoprints.; Theater collection.
Collection Contents
- 1. Academy Awards: photos1930 (Box 1)
  Norma Shearer, Conrad Nagel
- Academy Awards: photos1932 (Box 1)
  Louis B. Mayer, Helen Hayes, Hal Roach. Laurel & Hardy
- Academy Awards: photos1936 (Box 1)
  D.W. Griffith, Frank Capra, etc.
- Academy Awards: photos1937 (Box 1)
  Frank Capra, Paul Muni, Luise Rainer
- Academy Awards: photos1944 (Box 1)
  Paul Lukas, Jennifer Jones, Katina Paxinou, Charles Coburn
- Academy Awards: photos1945 (Box 1)
  Barry Fitzgerald, Ingrid Bergman, Bing Crosby
- 2. "The Adventures of Hajj Baba"1954, 18 (Box 1)
  (on-set shots) John Derek, Elaine
- 3. Barzin, Leon (Box 1)
  musical director, New York City Ballet
- 4. Baum, Vicki, 2 (Box 1)
  author of Grand Hotel
- 5. Berlin, Irving1929 (Box 1)
- 6. Bern, Paul1932 (Box 1)
  MGM exec
- 7. Burroughs, Edgar Rice1933 (Box 1)
  author of "Tarzan" stories on the set
- 8. Buzzell, Edward1936 (Box 1)
  Universal director
- 9. Clift, Denison (Box 1)
  director, writer
- 10. Cobb, Irwin S (Box 1)
  American humorist, wrote/acted for MGM, 1934
- 11. Cohen, Octavus Roy (Box 1)
  humorous writer signed with Universal
- 12. Cooper, Merian C. (Box 1)
  writer, RKO pictures
- 13. Corrigan, Lloyd (Box 1)
  director
- 14. Cruze, James, 4 (Box 1)
- 15. Curran, Homer, neg. (Box 1)
  owner, Curran Theatre, San Francisco
- 16. Dalton, Phyllis (Box 1)
  costume designer for "Oliver!"
- 17. Delmar, Vina (Box 1)
  author, MGM writer
- 18. De Mille, Cecil B., 17 (Box 1)
  stage actor, Paramount director
- 19. Densmore, Wess, 4 (Box 1)
  director, Laguna Beach Community Player
- 20. Dillon, J. Francis (Box 1)
  silent screen actor, sound film director
- 21. Disney, Walt, 8 (Box 1)
  studio and staff photos
- 22. Dunning, Philip1932 (Box 1)
  playwright and director
- 23. Early Film Shots: "David Garrick"1915 (Box 1)
  Vitagraph; Vera
- Reynolds in an early Chrislie Comedy; Zane Grey Film Company;1917 (Box 1)
  on location
- pic. of Lloyd Alexander; "Heart of the World" (Box 1)
- Ben Alexander; "A Daughter of the Gods"1916 (Box 1)
- "The Telephone Girl" (Box 1)
  Arthur Rankin and Alberta Vaughan; a few unidentified
- 24. Fowler, Gene1933 (Box 1)
  managing editor of the New York American and the New Telegraph; writer for Paramount Studios
- 25. Frohman, Daniel (Box 1)
  signed, 1927
- 26. Gershwin, George with Ginger Rogers1937, 2 (Box 1)
  composer
- 27. Gibbons, Floyd1932 (Box 1)
  war correspondent
- 28. Glass, Gaston1930 (Box 1)
  film actor, director
- 29. Goldberg, Rube (Box 1)
  Fox Studio comedy actor
- 30. Goldwyn, Samuel (Box 1)
- 31. Gordon, Mack1937 (Box 1)
  popular songwriter
- 32. Grey, Zane (Box 1)
  Western writer; see Early Film Shots folder
- 33. Griffith, D. W., 3 (Box 1)
  film director
- 34. Hall, Alexander (Box 1)
  (director) (photo with Shirley Temple and Baby Leroy, Paramount child stars)
- 35. Halliburton, Richard (Box 1)
  adventurer, author, appears in United Artists' "India Speaks"
- 36. Hammerstein, Oscar II (Box 1)
  co-author and co-producer of musical theatre, musical film with coposer Richard Rodgers; publicity still for release of "South pacific"
- 37. Hammett, Dashiell1934 (Box 1)
  (detective fiction author; "The Thin Man" publicity still with actor William Powell and director W.S.Van Dyke
- 38. Hayes, Will (Box 1)
  Samuel Goldwyn associate?
- 39. Hellman, Sam (Box 1)
  humorist and short story writer; wrote comedy for Fox Films
- 40. Hergesheimer, Joseph1932 (Box 1)
  German novelist
- 41. The Hollywood Museum: photos of opening ceremony1963 (Box 1)
  Walt Disney, Ronald Regan, Gregory peck, Warren Dorn, Edgar G. Robinson, Tommy Sands, Nancy Sinatra, Sebastian Cabot, Gloria Swanson, Jack Webb, Gene Autry, Ed Wynn, Cesar Romero, etc
- 42. Hollywood Scenes: Fox Studios (Box 1)
  aerial shot of RKO Radio Studios
- Studios, Paramount Studiosca. 1927 (Box 1)
- Universal City1916 (Box 1)
- Universal City snowstorm1914 (Box 1)
- The Thirteenth Christian Science Church1933 (Box 1)
  interior of the Brown Derby, crowd at premiere of "Cavalcade" at Grauman's Chinese Theatre
- 43. Howard, Joe 1942 (Box 1)
  publisher
- 44. Hughes, Rupert (Box 1)
  musician, composer, novelist and photoplaywright
- 45. Hurst, Fannie (Box 1)
  author; story made into film by Paramount Pictures
- 46. Jones, Robert Edmond (Box 1)
- 47. Kane, Whitford (Box 1)
- 48. Kaufman, George (Box 1)
- 49. (on set shots) "Key Largo"1947 (Box 1)
  Humphrey Bogart, Lauren Bacall, Thomas Gomez
- 50. Kirstein, Lincoln (Box 1)
  general director, New York City Ballet
- 51. Laemmle, Carl, 12 (Box 1)
  film pioneer; pres. of Universal Studios
- 52. Lasky, Jesse1936, 3 (Box 1)
  producer?
- 53. Lawrence, Vincent1931 (Box 1)
  playwright signed with Paramount
- 54. Lee, Jack (Box 1)
  British film director
- 55. Lloyd, Frank (Box 1)
  director for Goldwyn
- 56. Locke, William J. (Box 1)
  novelist, screen writer
- 57. Logan, Joshua (Box 1)
  co-author and director of "Mr. Roberts"
- 58. Lombardo, Guy (Box 1)
  famous radio personality, conductor
- 59. Loos, Anita, 5 (Box 1)
  author of novels and screenplays; "Gentlemen Prefer Blondes"; subtitler for silents
- 60. Lubitsch, Ernst 1936, 10 (Box 1)
- 61. McDonald, Frank 1937 (Box 1)
- 62. Macpherson, Jeanie (Box 1)
  air pilot, screenwriter
- 63. Maugham, Somerset 1934 (Box 1)
  writer
- 64. Marion, Frances, 2 (Box 1)
  screenwriter, screen editor for MGM
- 65. Mayer, Arthur, 3 negatives (Box 1)
  writer?
- 66. Mencken, H. L., 2 (Box 1)
  literary critic, satirist
- 67. Milestone, Lewis (Box 1)
- 68. Millay, Edna St. Vincent 1933 (Box 1)
  American poet
- 69. Miller, Arthur (Box 1)
  playwright
- 70. Mizner, Wilson1933 (Box 1)
  drama critic, Hollywood and Broadway
- 71. Nichols, Anne (Box 1)
  author, "Abie's Irish Rose", play and Paramount picture
- 72. Ostrer, Mark 1936, 4 (Box 1)
  chairman of the board, GB Pictures
- 73. Parsons, Louella (Box 1)
  gossip columnist
- 74. Pasternack, Joseph 1937 (Box 1)
  film producer
- 75. Publicity: photos, negatives; "Hitler's Children," (Box 1)
  contest to win the "Panther Woman" film role in Paramount's "Island of Lost Souls"
- 76. Rainger, Ralph (Box 1)
  Paramount song writer
- 77. Rapper, Irving 1937 (Box 1)
  dialogue director, Warner Brothers
- 78. Reed, Sir Carol, 3 and press release (Box 1)
- 79. Renoir, Jean, 3 (Box 1)
  French film director
- 80. Rialto Theatre: Los Angeles (?), 4 photos, 2 negatives of (Box 1)
  movie house
- 81. Roach, Hal (Box 1)
  comedy film producer, director, writer
- 82. Rodgers, Richard (Box 1)
  composer, musical theatre and film partner with Oscar Hammerstein II
- 83. Rohmer, Sax 1932 (Box 1)
  author of the "Fu Manchu" stories
- 84. Romberg, Sigmund (Box 1)
  music arranger and conductor
- 85. Rosenthal, Jean (Box 1)
  production director, New York City Ballet
- 86. Ruth, Babe, 3 (Box 1)
  baseball player
- 87. St. John, Adela R. (Box 2)
  Malibu resident
- 88. Sarnoff, David (Box 2)
  president of Radio Corporation of America
- 89. Saroyan, William (Box 2)
  author, The Time of Your Life
- 90. Schlesinger, Leon 1937 (Box 2)
  producer of "Merrie Melodies" and "Looney Tunes" for Warner Brothers
- 91. Schulberg, B.1937 (Box 2)
- 92. Sennett, Mack, 7 (Box 2)
  comedy film producer
- 93. Shaw, George Bernard (Box 2)
  British author
- 94. Shepheard's Supper Club: New York supper club and discotheque (Box 2)
  opened 1963
- 95. Sherriff, R. C.1932 (Box 2)
  British author; screenplay adapter
- 96. Sherwood, Robert E. (Box 2)
- 97. Simon, Neil 1964 (Box 2)
  playwright; "Barefoot in the Park"
- 98. Sobol, Louis (Box 2)
  film shorts producer for Universal Studios
- 99. Stewart, Donald Ogden (Box 2)
  humorist; writer; bit-player
- 100. Stokowski, Leopold (Box 2)
  orchestra conductor; in "100 Men and a Girl" with Deanna Durbin
- 101. Sturges, Preston 1932 (Box 2)
  author; screenplay adapter
- 102. Taylor, Samuel (Box 2)
- 103. Thorpe, Richard 1935 (Box 2)
  MGM director
- 104. Tolstoy, Count Leo 1934 (Box 2)
  author
- 105. (on set shots) "Trapeze" 1956 (Box 2)
  Tony Curtis, Thomas Gomez, Burt Lancaster
- 106. Van Dyne, S. S. 1931 (Box 2)
  analyst, detective fiction writer, film dialogue writer
- 107. Vidor, Charles "King", 2 (Box 2)
- 108. Von Stroheim, Eric, 2 (Box 2)
  film director, actor
- 109. Wanger, Walter 1937, 4 (Box 2)
- 110. Waring, Fred (Box 2)
  band leader, bit player
- 111. Watson, William (Box 2)
  film director, Paramount-Christie Comedies
- 112. Webster, Margaret (Box 2)
- 113. White House Luncheon: film stars with Eleanor Roosevelt; fundraiser (Box 2)
- 114. Winchell, Walter, 3 (Box 2)
  journalist
- 115. Zukor, Adolph, 5 (Box 2)
  chairman of the board of directors, Paramount Productions; film producer